DR. SUSAN JEWELL: Hello.
Now in this clip, we're going to talk about alternative way versus the conventional way of treating fevers but brief--and that's the herbal, herbal remedies.
There are a lot of herbal remedies, herbs out there that are readily available in your health food stores and drug stores that have properties to reduce the fever or anti--they have antipyretic properties, so you can take those but before you ever take any kind of herbal remedies, you should always consult with your medical doctor and get his or her advice first before you start on any of this kind of herbal therapy.
Now here I have some samples of some forms of herbs, and also I have vitamins 'cause vitamins are also good to take to prevent fevers, to prevent illnesses.
But some of the herbs I've known, for example, you can get herbs that are already incorporated into drinks like in the tea bags, here I have chamomile tea, and even if you have fevers and you cannot ingest food or solids, then tea is actually a good way to replenish your fluid intake to prevent dehydration.
So here's chamomile tea that's readily available, and here is a Japanese tea, herbal tea that you can also buy, green tea.
Green tea is good, if you can, because it has a lot of anti-oxidants in it as well.
So, that would also help you during the time to prevent fevers, and also to treat the symptoms of fever and to prevent dehydration while you're going through a bout of high fever, high temperature from the vomiting and the diarrhea.
So, here you have chamomile.
Chamomile is good also.
This is a tablet form but most of the time, when you have a high temperature and it's associated with vomiting, you probably won't like to swallow tablets, so it's better to buy in these formulations, in tea bags or in food additives.
Or you could use it to rub on to the body for like aromatherapy treatment.
But as I mentioned earlier, it's good to also, to prevent fevers and high temperatures from fevers, is to do prevention, and that is also to have your daily recommended dose of vitamins and minerals.
Vitamin C to prevent colds, and here, the B complex, this is too, so, a multivitamin.
So, these are some ways that you can actually help to reduce, and prevent, and reduce the symptoms of fever.